NIKOLAY SHATALOV

Software Engineer

(201) 912-9872 <u>nikoobox@gmail.com</u> <u>Portfolio</u> <u>LinkedIn</u> <u>Github</u> New York, NY

Skills

JavaScript, React, Redux, HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Mongoose, MongoDB, Node.js, Express.js, SQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite3, Webpack, jQuery, Git, Heroku, Amazon Web Services (AWS), D3.js

Projects

TreeCamp (JavaScript, React/Redux, Ruby/Rails, HTML5, CSS3, PostgreSQL, AWS)

Live Site | Github

TreeCamp is a full-stack Hipcamp clone that allows users to discover and book unique treehouses.

- Optimized backend routes and shape of front-end state to minimize load-time for process-heavy user experience (UX), such as user login, that heavily depends on the previously saved credentials.
- Utilized Redux single-state management to establish communication between backend and frontend environment and implement CRUD functionality.
- Implemented fully responsive modals and animations to simplify UX when navigating through the website.
- Leveraged AWS S3 for image storage imposing a file size limit and file compression to reduce the storage cost.

90 Plus (JavaScript, Node.js, Express.js, D3.js, HTML5, CSS3, Firebase/Firestore) *An interactive soccer live score app with dynamic data and visualizations.*

Live Site | Github

- Integrated Football-API by using promise based HTTP client Axios to receive, display and update the most recent soccer data.
- Utilizing Node.js platform on backend to securely store API keys and set asynchronous API routes.
- Implemented live updates by using local storage to temporarily save data and keep track of number of page reloads.
- Harnessed the power of serverless Cloud Firestore realtime NoSQL database by syncing user's voting data.

Pomegranate (JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, MongoDB, Mongoose, Express.js, React/Redux, Node.js) <u>Live Site</u> | <u>Github</u> A web-app that generates unique recipes based on the ingredients from user's kitchen

- Adopted Babel and Webpack to support seamless and uniform visual experience across web browsers.
- Headed front-end design and development by adding pleasant, minimalistic look and smooth navigation ensured by React-Router components

Experience

New York Temperature Controls: **Application Engineer**

Sep 2018 - Sep 2020

- Developed efficient mechanical and automated Building Management Systems (BMS) designs and engineering control submittals
- Entirely redesigned over 50% of existing graphical user interfaces (GUI) for BMS and HVAC systems and developed new design standards for the company.
- Created javascript code to speed-up the process of building typical GUI graphics reducing number of errors.
- Tested and modified control programs with Niagara Framework software prior to releasing.

TEC Systems: Control Systems Engineer

Jun 2017 - Sep 2018

- Designed electrical wiring and flow diagrams on mechanical blueprints.
- Implemented and utilized AutoCad on a daily basis for high level engineering and drafting.

Education

App Academy Aug 2020 - Dec 2020

Immersive software development course with focus on full stack web development.

The City College of New York

Bachelor's in Mechanical Engineering

Sep 2013 - Dec 2017